# **JAKE PORTER**

Oklahoma City Area | <u>Jake.m.porter@gmail.com</u> | 405-464-2755 github.com/Jakemporter | linkedin.com/in/jakemporter/

#### **FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

I'm a software engineer with experience testing and troubleshooting software. Knowing how code breaks gives me a stronger ability to write clean code and collaborate with others in the engineering workflow. I have a critical eye for when data and web-pages are looking off and thrive on working to improve software and user experience.

# **SKILLS**

Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, Node, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Dental Intelligence | Jr. Software Developer Dental Intelligence | QA Engineer

May 2019 - March 2021 March 2021 - Present

- Decrease production time for new software being released by finding bugs and making sure they are fixed quickly.
- Developed several automated regression tests using cypress and playwright and javascript that cover most of the UI.
- Organize spreadsheets of the process used for eliminating bugs from to-do, in progress, testing stage, to finished. This allows for bugs that are not fixed yet to quickly be addressed and a way for other developers to easily see what bugs need to be fixed.
- Test the pre-production software for bugs and check if there are irregularities between the current version and the pre-production software. This allowed pre-production software to reach consumers faster.

# **Actualize | Software Engineer**

**July 2020 - November 2020** 

- Capstone Project (Car Auction): personally built a web app that allows users to bid on cars on the
  website for a specified time limit. Allows other users to sign in and create auctions to sell their cars.
  Cars that are being auctioned have multiple pictures, detailed descriptions, more vehicle information
  and current auction values from the API using the VIN. Built in Ruby on Rails and PostgreSQL for
  the back-end and HTML, CSS and JavaScript for the front-end.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
  - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
  - o Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
  - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styles results, incorporated libraries and themes

Other: Lawn Maintenance - Trails Golf Course | Car Detailing - Auto Image USA

# **EDUCATION**

University of Central Oklahoma - General Coursework in Computer Science - 2018 - 2020 Norman North Highschool - High School Diploma - 2014 - 2018